<deck id="1268191010" name="NI-NUR::NI-NUR-01" deck_slug="NI-NUR-01">

    <note id="1999196441" type="1708237251">
        <div class="field">
Proces návrhu uživatelských rozhraní
        </div>
        <div class="field">
<ol><li>Product statement (what it does for whom, what it does not)</li><li>Personas - models of users (typical user, occasional user, etc.)</li><li>UseCases and Scenarios (use case is a list of actions defining the interactions between an actor and a system, use cases are derived from the business requirements)</li><li>WireFrames (schematic focusing on what the screen does, actions available to the user, etc.)</li><li>Prototypes (Lo-Fi/Hi-Fi)</li></ol>
        </div>
    </note>
    <note id="1738406647" type="1708237251">
        <div class="field">
Mentální model
        </div>
        <div class="field">
<ul>
  <li>The user has a mental model of how the program works. When this mental model does not fit the reality, issues arise, usually the user has issues with using the product and that makes them feel stupid.</li>
</ul>
        </div>
    </note>
    <note id="1199301791" type="1708237251">
        <div class="field">
Limity lidské paměti
        </div>
        <div class="field">
<ul>
  <li>The short term memory can hold 3-5 "items" at once. The average user will have issues using a program that assumes they can hold more than 3 "items" at once in their short term memory.</li>
</ul>
        </div>
    </note>
    <note id="1506472806" type="1708237251">
        <div class="field">
Lidské vnímání
        </div>
        <div class="field">
<ul>
  <li>Complementary colors are colors which cancel out (result in gray when mixed). That results in good contrast when used in UI. It is also common to use triadic color schemes (three colors evenly spaced on the color wheel) or tetradic color schemes (two pairs of complementary colors).</li>
  <li>Different colors have different cultural associations (e.g. warm colors such as red tend to evoke energy and action, cool colors such as blue tend to evoke calmness...)</li>
</ul>
        </div>
    </note>

</deck>